<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home</title>
    <link>https://lgbouma.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lgbouma.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/bio/</guid>
      <description>I was born in Bethesda, MD, and grew up in the circumference of a hadron collider in Switzerland, in a valley between the Jura and the Alps.
I graduated from the University of Southern California in 2015 with Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees in physics and math. I completed my doctoral studies at Princeton&amp;rsquo;s Department of Astrophysical Sciences in 2021, advised by Josh Winn. I continued my research as a 51 Pegasi b fellow at Caltech from 2021 to 2024, and I currently work as a Carnegie Fellow at the Observatories of the Carnegie Institution for Science, also in Pasadena, California.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/bio_gradschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/bio_gradschool/</guid>
      <description>bio Luke was born in Bethesda, MD. He grew up in the circumference of a hadron collider in Switzerland, in a valley between the Jura and the Alps.
He graduated from USC with Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees in physics and mathematics.
He began graduate work in physics at MIT with Josh Winn, and transferred to Princeton to continue the same.
Over graduate school, he has enjoyed fruitful collaboration with the TESS science team, as well as the architects and executors of the HAT Exoplanet Surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>email: lbouma at carnegiescience dot edu
location: Carnegie Observatories, office 227
name pronunciation: my last name sounds like &amp;ldquo;bao-muh&amp;rdquo;.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/links/</guid>
      <description>Astronomy Tools
TESS light curve inspector by Julien de Lambilly
Nearby clusters and HR diagram by Marina Kounkel
simbad
vizier
Sound
MyNoise
Futurescapes
Omar and friends
Perspective
Gapminder
The Younger Dryas
Incarceration in the United States</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/longformresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/longformresearch/</guid>
      <description>Young Transiting Planets A major component of my thesis is the Cluster Difference Imaging Photometric Survey. While thousands of exoplanets are known, most orbit field stars with poorly measured ages between 1 and 10 billion years. I have been using TESS to find planets around cluster stars in groups younger than 1 billion years. This paper introduces the project, and this preprint validates a 40 million year old planet. Light curves from Year 1 of TESS are available on MAST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/notes/</guid>
      <description>CDIPS Light Curves 2023.11.12. The CDIPS light curves for Sector 27 to 55 of TESS are available at MAST. A cumulative metadata file is also available at the HLSP page.
2022.05.04. The CDIPS light curves for Sectors 14 to 26 of TESS are available at MAST. A cumulative metadata file is also on the HLSP page. Reductions for Cycle 3 are underway!
2020.08.25. The CDIPS light curves for Sectors 1 to 13 of TESS are available at MAST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/oddities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/oddities/</guid>
      <description>Clouds in New Jersey, ca. 2019.
Me by the turtle pond. March, 2021.
Saturn. The Cassini Division is visible, and is caused by a 2:1 resonance with Mimas. The image is from the 12&amp;quot; Meade LX200 in Peyton&amp;rsquo;s Observatory, acquired using a Canon EOS 60D. August, 2017.
Thimbleberry in Montana. Easily confused for raspberry. August, 2022.
Good fall colors in Princeton, outside Peyton Hall. September, 2017.
Sienna, posing on remains of Mount Lowe Railway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Young Planets in Star Clusters While thousands of exoplanets are known, most are billions of years old. I have used TESS, Gaia, and Kepler to find and study planets around stars in clusters younger than one billion years. The properties of these young planets help clarify the processes that sculpted present-day distributions of exoplanet sizes, atmospheres, and orbital geometries.
Click here to learn more →  Kepler and the Behemoth: Three Mini-Neptunes in a 40 Million Year Old Association [Paper]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Observatory That Wasn&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/posts/1/01/the-observatory-that-wasnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/posts/1/01/the-observatory-that-wasnt/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Neither Suphis the monarch of Egypt, nor Rameses II, nor the builders of Nineveh, did greater work. Engineers from every nation on Earth have studied this wondrous electric road from Pasadena to the base of Mount Lowe and have pronounced it one of the chief monuments reared by human hands.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Edgar L. Larkin, 1901.
In astronomical circles, the Mount Wilson Observatory commands a great deal of reverence. Historically, the observatory&amp;rsquo;s main claim to fame is the 100-inch Hooker telescope, which was the world&amp;rsquo;s largest telescope from 1917 to 1949.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
