<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lgbouma</title>
    <link>https://lgbouma.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on lgbouma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://lgbouma.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/bio/</guid>
      <description>Luke was born in Bethesda, MD. He grew up in the circumference of a hadron collider in Switzerland, in a valley between the Jura and the Alps.
He graduated from USC in 2015 with Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees in physics and mathematics. He began graduate work in physics at MIT with Josh Winn, and transferred to Princeton to continue the same. He completed his doctoral studies in Princeton&amp;rsquo;s Department of Astrophysical Sciences in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/bio_gradschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/bio_gradschool/</guid>
      <description>bio Luke was born in Bethesda, MD. He grew up in the circumference of a hadron collider in Switzerland, in a valley between the Jura and the Alps.
He graduated from USC with Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees in physics and mathematics.
He began graduate work in physics at MIT with Josh Winn, and transferred to Princeton to continue the same.
Over graduate school, he has enjoyed fruitful collaboration with the TESS science team, as well as the architects and executors of the HAT Exoplanet Surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>email: luke at astro dot caltech dot edu
location: Cahill Center for Astronomy and Astrophysics, 2nd floor, room 220
name pronunciation: my last name rhymes with &amp;ldquo;wow-phở&amp;rdquo;.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/longformresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/longformresearch/</guid>
      <description>Young Transiting Planets A major component of my thesis is the Cluster Difference Imaging Photometric Survey. While thousands of exoplanets are known, most orbit field stars with poorly measured ages between 1 and 10 billion years. I have been using TESS to find planets around cluster stars in groups younger than 1 billion years. This paper introduces the project, and this preprint validates a 40 million year old planet. Light curves from Year 1 of TESS are available on MAST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/notes/</guid>
      <description>CDIPS ExoFOP Documentation 2022.02.19. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted new CDIPS planet candidates to ExoFOP-TESS, based on the second year of TESS images (Sectors 14 to 26). You can find them at the CTOI table. The light curves are staged (and in holding) at MAST. Relevant documentation is below. Since it can be somewhat difficult to pull everything off ExoFOP, this dropbox folder is an alternative way to download everything from one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/oddities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/oddities/</guid>
      <description>Clouds in New Jersey, ca. 2019.
Me by the turtle pond. March, 2021.
Saturn. The Cassini Division is visible, and is caused by a 2:1 resonance with Mimas. I took the images through the 12&amp;quot; Meade LX200 in Peyton&amp;rsquo;s Observatory, using a Canon EOS 60D. August, 2017.
Me next to a river. August, 2020.
Good fall colors in Princeton, outside Peyton Hall. September, 2017.
Rocks next to a water spout in Nevada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/research/</guid>
      <description>Young Stars and their Planets While thousands of exoplanets are known, most orbit field stars with poorly measured ages between 1 and 10 billion years. I have been using TESS, Gaia, and Kepler to find and characterize planets around stars in open clusters and moving groups younger than 1 billion years. Related articles include:
  A 38 Million Year Old Mini-Neptune in the Kepler Field. (Paper, Table 3).
  Rotation and Lithium Confirmation of a 500 Parsec Halo for the Open Cluster NGC 2516.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Observatory That Wasn&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://lgbouma.com/posts/1/01/the-observatory-that-wasnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lgbouma.com/posts/1/01/the-observatory-that-wasnt/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Neither Suphis the monarch of Egypt, nor Rameses II, nor the builders of Nineveh, did greater work. Engineers from every nation on Earth have studied this wondrous electric road from Pasadena to the base of Mount Lowe and have pronounced it one of the chief monuments reared by human hands.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Edgar L. Larkin, 1901.
In astronomical circles, the Mount Wilson Observatory commands a great deal of reverence. Historically, the observatory&amp;rsquo;s main claim to fame is the 100-inch Hooker telescope, which was the world&amp;rsquo;s largest telescope from 1917 to 1949.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
